Guide to the Darrin Zammit Lupi photojournalism archive, 2004-2017 RL.11613
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- On Board the Aquarius, 2017 December 15-19; 1.5 Linear Feet 1 box 20 photographic prints; 16.73 Gigabytes 3210 files (110 tiff, 3035 jpg, 46 png, 11 mp4, 3 pdf, 2 doc, 1 VLC, 1 txt, and 1 xls)
  - Large photographic prints, 2017 December 15-18; 20 prints 1 box 20x24 inches
    - Migrants transferred from Open Arms 3, 2017 December 16 (Box 1, Image RL.11613-P-0007)
    - Migrant baby brought to Aquarius 3, 2017 December 16 (Box 1, Image RL.11613-P-0008)
    - Migrant stands on deck, 2017 December 17 (Box 1, Image RL.11613-P-0009)
    - Migrants rest on Aquarius 7, 2017 December 17 (Box 1, Image RL.11613-P-0010)
    - Migrant rests 1, 2017 December 17 (Box 1, Image RL.11613-P-0011)
    - Migrants sit, 2017 December 18 (Box 1, Image RL.11613-P-0012)
    - Migrants wait on Aquarius off Pozzallo 1, 2017 December 18 (Box 1, Image RL.11613-P-0013)
    - Migrants wait on Aquarius off Pozzallo 2, 2017 December 18 (Box 1, Image RL.11613-P-0014)
    - Migrants wait on Aquarius off Pozzallo 11, 2017 December 18 (Box 1, Image RL.11613-P-0015)
    - Migrants sing and dance 2, 2017 December 18 (Box 1, Image RL.11613-P-0016)
    - Migrant child looks through porthole, 2017 December 18 (Box 1, Image RL.11613-P-0017)
    - Migrants wait to disembark 6, 2017 December 18 (Box 1, Image RL.11613-P-0018)
    - Italian soldiers near medical tent, 2017 December 18 (Box 1, Image RL.11613-P-0019)
    - Migrants wait to disembark 7, 2017 December 18 (Box 1, Image RL.11613-P-0020)
  - Thumbnails and contact sheets (electronic files), 2017 December 15-19; 3035 low-resolution image jpg files, 26 digital contact sheets as png files (.893 GB)
    This series contains electronic records that must be requested through the collection guide and accessed in the Rubenstein Library reading room. Note: tiff images are immediately accessible through links in this collection guide.
    Organized by topical group in original order. All titles are from photographer's data.
    - Rescue operation, 2017 December 15-19 (Digital-materials RL11613-SET-0002)
    - Mid-sea transfer, 2017 December 16 (Digital-materials RL11613-SET-0002)
    - Post-rescue at sea, 2017 December 17 (Digital-materials RL11613-SET-0002)
    - Arrival in Pozzallo, Sicily, 2017 December 18 (Digital-materials RL11613-SET-0002)
  - Videos, 2017 December 15-19; 10 files (9 mp4, 1 Word doc); 3.3 GB
    Word document is a 2-page script corresponding to Darrin Zammit Lupi news report video.
    This series contains electronic records that must be requested through the collection guide and accessed in the Rubenstein Library reading room.
    - Aquarius rescue, 2017 December 15; 1 mp4 file; 418 MB; running time 5 minutes, 44 seconds (Digital-materials RL11613-SET-0003)
    - Aquarius, evening, 2017 December 17; 1 mp4 file; 125 MB; running time 1 minute, 43 seconds (Digital-materials RL11613-SET-0003)
    - Aquarius transfer from Open Arms, 2017 December; 1 mp4 file; 346 MB; running time 4 minutes, 46 seconds (Digital-materials RL11613-SET-0003)
    - Migrants on the Aquarius, 2017 December 17; 1 mp4 file; 129 MB; running time 1 minutes, 46 seconds (Digital-materials RL11613-SET-0003)
    - Interview: Luca Salerno, MSF on the Aquarius, 2017 December 17; 1 mp4 file; 212 MB; running time 2 minutes, 54 seconds (Digital-materials RL11613-SET-0003)
    - Interview: Nwankwo Johnson, 25 years old, Nigeria, 2017 December; 1 mp4 file; 316 MB; running time 4 minutes, 19 seconds (Digital-materials RL11613-SET-0003)
    - Interview: Ruth Nso, 29 years old, Cameroon, 2017 December; 1 mp4 file; 1.15 GB; running time 16 minutes, 11 seconds (Digital-materials RL11613-SET-0003)
    - Aquarius arrives in Pozzallo, Sicily, 2017 December 18; 1 mp4 file; 474 MB; running time 6 minutes, 31 seconds (Digital-materials RL11613-SET-0003)
    - Darrin Zammit Lupi Reuters news report, 2017 December 18; 1 mp4 file; 174 MB; running time 2 minutes, 28 seconds (Digital-materials RL11613-SET-0003)
    - RTR TV APP script Aquarius, 2017 December 18; 1 file (MS Word doc); 124 KB (Digital-materials RL11613-SET-0003)
  - Other documentation (electronic files), 2017 December 15-19; 34 files (png, mp4, pdf, doc, xls, txt, VLC); approximately 7 MB
    - Journal and other data created by Zammit Lupi, 2017 December 15-19; 3 files (Excel xls, Adobe pdf, MS Word doc); 10.2 MB (Digital-materials RL11613-SET-0004)
      Includes scans from Zammit Lupi's 16-page journal, and an Excel data file on the migrants, listing gender, age, and origin. A Word document lists news sources that reposted the Reuter's reports by Zammit Lupi, including Italian, French, Spanish, Czech, Arabic, Korean, Dutch, Turkish, and Israeli news outlets.
    - Published videos and shotlists, 2017 December 15-21; 5 files (2 mp4, 1 VLC, 2 txt); 1.14 GB (Digital-materials RL11613-SET-0004)
    - Reuters social media posts during mission, 2017 December 15-19; 7 files (png); 4.27 MB (Digital-materials RL11613-SET-0004)
      Images are in the form of screen shots from Reuters social media outlets on Facebook (2), Twitter (4), and Instagram (1).
    - SOS Méditeranée press releases, 2017 December 15-19; 7 files (6 png; 1 pdf); 3.4 MB (Digital-materials RL11613-SET-0004)
      The press release (Adobe pdf) is in French. Several screenshots are also in French.
    - SOS Méditeranée social media posts, 2017 December 15-19; 8 files (7 png; 1 pdf); 2.87 MB (Digital-materials RL11613-SET-0004)
      Files consist of screen shots from Facebook and Twitter. Most of the posts originating from the SOS Méditeranée are in French.
- Malta Detention, 2004-2013; 1.5 Linear Feet 1 box 20 photographic prints; 12.57 Gigabytes 1821 files (147 tiff, 1646 jpeg, 20 png, 8 pdf)
  The color photographs in this series were taken by photojournalist Darrin Zammit Lupi over a period of nine years in detention camps for undocumented migrants near Valletta, the capital city of Malta. The images document migrants, chiefly from West Africa and Sub-Saharan regions, as they wait, sometimes for 18 months, for a decision on their status. There are close-up portraits of individuals, as well as group shots; settings include interiors as well as outside areas. There are photographs of immigrants protesting conditions in the camps and a few of immigrants on their way to trials in court. One sequence records Jacques Barrot, European Commissioner, visiting a detention center and meeting with protesters. All prints measure approximately 20x24 inches.
  Electronic records (1821 files) also form an important part of this series. All images are in color. They include 147 tiff files; 1646 low-resolution jpegs from which the larger images were selected; 20 png images of contact sheets; and eight pdfs of Times of Malta newspaper articles on migrant detention camps, featuring Lupi's photographic work. The tiff images are immediately available through links in this series.
  Collection contains electronic records that must be requested through the collection guide and accessed in the Rubenstein Library reading room.
  The photographic prints are arranged in original order as received.
  - TIFF images (electronic files), 2004-2013; 147 files (.tif); 12 GB
    - Lunch under a tree, 2004 July 25; Original file id: BE9A2308 (Digital-materials RL11613-SET-0005, Image-file RL.11613-TIFF-0111)
      An Armed Forces of Malta soldier sits with Illegal immigrants under a tree at the detention centre at Safi barracks in Safi, outside Valletta, July 25, 2004. Photo: Darrin Zammit Lupi
    - Banners for journalists, 2006 March 23; Original file id: BE9A1847 (Digital-materials RL11613-SET-0005, Image-file RL.11613-TIFF-0112)
      Illegal immigrants watch visiting journalists as banners demanding their freedom hang at a detention centre in the Armed Forces of Malta Safi barracks, outside Valletta, March 23, 2006. Around 1,000 illegal immigrants are currently in detention in Malta. The Malta government insists the immigrants must be held in detention because their large numbers may cause problems to the economy, while the immigrants say they never intended to come to Malta in the first place and want to be allowed to go to Italy. A delegation of European Members of Parliament is visiting Malta in the coming days to draw up a report on illegal immigration. Photo: Darrin Zammit Lupi
    - Hard stares through the fence, 2006 March 23; Original file id: _C4W2685 (Digital-materials RL11613-SET-0005, Image-file RL.11613-TIFF-0113)
      Illegal immigrants watch visiting journalists at a detention centre in the Armed Forces of Malta Safi barracks, outside Valletta, March 23, 2006. Around 1,000 illegal immigrants are currently in detention in Malta. The Malta government insists the immigrants must be held in detention because their large numbers may cause problems to the economy, while the immigrants say they never intended to come to Malta in the first place and want to be allowed to go to Italy. A delegation of European Members of Parliament is visiting Malta in the coming days to draw up a report on illegal immigration. Photo: Darrin Zammit Lupi
    - Photos of home, 2006 March 23; Original file id: BE9A1863 (Digital-materials RL11613-SET-0005, Image-file RL.11613-TIFF-0114)
      An illegal immigrant shows visiting journalists photographs of his family back home, at a detention centre in the Armed Forces of Malta Safi barracks, outside Valletta, March 23, 2006. Around 1,000 illegal immigrants are currently in detention in Malta. The Malta government insists the immigrants must be held in detention because their large numbers may cause problems to the economy, while the immigrants say they never intended to come to Malta in the first place and want to be allowed to go to Italy. A delegation of European Members of Parliament is visiting Malta in the coming days to draw up a report on illegal immigration. Photo: Darrin Zammit Lupi
    - "Set the captive free", 2006 March 23; Original file id: _C4W2738 (Digital-materials RL11613-SET-0005, Image-file RL.11613-TIFF-0115)
      Illegal immigrants watch visiting journalists as a banner demanding their freedom hangs on a wall at a detention centre in the Armed Forces of Malta Safi barracks, outside Valletta, March 23, 2006. Around 1,000 illegal immigrants are currently in detention in Malta. The Malta government insists the immigrants must be held in detention because their large numbers may cause problems to the economy, while the immigrants say they never intended to come to Malta in the first place and want to be allowed to go to Italy. A delegation of European Members of Parliament is visiting Malta in the coming days to draw up a report on illegal immigration. Photo: Darrin Zammit Lupi
    - On a bed in the courtyard, 2006 March 23; Original file id: BE9A1867 (Digital-materials RL11613-SET-0005, Image-file RL.11613-TIFF-0116)
      Illegal immigrants sit in an enclosed compound at a detention centre in the Armed Forces of Malta Safi barracks, outside Valletta, March 23, 2006. Around 1,000 illegal immigrants are currently in detention in Malta. The Malta government insists the immigrants must be held in detention because their large numbers may cause problems to the economy, while the immigrants say they never intended to come to Malta in the first place and want to be allowed to go to Italy. A delegation of European Members of Parliament is visiting Malta in the coming days to draw up a report on illegal immigration. Photo: Darrin Zammit Lupi
    - Incarceration, 2006 March 23; Original file id: BE9A1900 (Digital-materials RL11613-SET-0005, Image-file RL.11613-TIFF-0117)
      An illegal immigrant holds onto a perimeter fence at a detention centre in the Armed Forces of Malta Safi barracks, outside Valletta March 23, 2006.Around 1,000 illegal immigrants are currently in detention in Malta. The Malta government insists the immigrants must be held in detention because their large numbers may cause problems to the economy, while the immigrants say they never intended to come to Malta in the first place and want to be allowed to go to Italy. A delegation of European Members of Parliament is visiting Malta in the coming days to draw up a report on illegal immigration. Photo: Darrin Zammit Lupi
    - "18 months is too much", 2006 March 23; Original file id: _C4W2819 (Digital-materials RL11613-SET-0005, Image-file RL.11613-TIFF-0118)
      Illegal immigrants hold a banner protesting against their detention at a detention centre in the Armed Forces of Malta Lyster barracks, outside Valletta, March 23, 2006. Around 1,000 illegal immigrants are currently in detention in Malta. The Malta government insists the immigrants must be held in detention because their large numbers may cause problems to the economy, while the immigrants say they never intended to come to Malta in the first place and want to be allowed to go to Italy. A delegation of European Members of Parliament is visiting Malta in the coming days to draw up a report on illegal immigration. Photo: Darrin Zammit Lupi
    - Despairing immigrant at Lyster barracks detention centre, 2006 March 23; Original file id: _C4W2891 (Digital-materials RL11613-SET-0005, Image-file RL.11613-TIFF-0119)
      An illegal immigrant cries as he hangs onto a perimeter fence at a detention centre in the Armed Forces of Malta Lyster barracks, outside Valletta, March 23, 2006. Around 1,000 illegal immigrants are currently in detention in Malta. The Malta government insists the immigrants must be held in detention because their large numbers may cause problems to the economy, while the immigrants say they never intended to come to Malta in the first place and want to be allowed to go to Italy. A delegation of European Members of Parliament is visiting Malta in the coming days to draw up a report on illegal immigration. Photo: Darrin Zammit Lupi
    - Behind the wire, 2006 March 23; Original file id: BE9A1934 (Digital-materials RL11613-SET-0005, Image-file RL.11613-TIFF-0120)
      Illegal immigrants gesture towards journalists at a detention centre in the Armed Forces of Malta Lyster barracks, outside Valletta, March 23, 2006. Around 1,000 illegal immigrants are currently in detention in Malta. The Malta government insists the immigrants must be held in detention because their large numbers may cause problems to the economy, while the immigrants say they never intended to come to Malta in the first place and want to be allowed to go to Italy. A delegation of European Members of Parliament is visiting Malta in the coming days to draw up a report on illegal immigration. Photo: Darrin Zammit Lupi
    - Waiting for supplies, 2006 June 4; Original file id: _C4W4911 (Digital-materials RL11613-SET-0005, Image-file RL.11613-TIFF-0121)
      Two handcuffed illegal immigrants look through a fence as they receive supplies from friends outside the wire at Safi barracks detention centre June 4, 2006. Photo: Darrin Zammit Lupi
    - Killing time (1), 2008 July 15; Original file id: _JM97703 (Digital-materials RL11613-SET-0005, Image-file RL.11613-TIFF-0122)
      An African would-be immigrant sleeps on a mattress in an enclosed compound at the Safi detention centre outside Valletta July 15, 2008. Around 1,500 illegal immigrants are currently held in detention in Malta for periods of up to 18 months. Though their intention was to reach Italy, most found themselves in Malta when they were rescued by the Maltese Armed Forces when they found themselves in difficulties while on their way to reach European soil from Africa. Photo: Darrin Zammit Lupi
    - On the window sill, 2008 July 15; Original file id: _C4W1403 (Digital-materials RL11613-SET-0005, Image-file RL.11613-TIFF-0123)
      African would-be immigrants sit on a window sill in an enclosed compound at the Safi detention centre outside Valletta July 15, 2008. Around 1,500 illegal immigrants are currently held in detention in Malta for periods of up to 18 months. Though their intention was to reach Italy, most found themselves in Malta when they were rescued by the Maltese Armed Forces when they found themselves in difficulties while on their way to reach European soil from Africa. Photo: Darrin Zammit Lupi
    - Killing time (2), 2008 July 15; Original file id: _JM97726 (Digital-materials RL11613-SET-0005, Image-file RL.11613-TIFF-0124)
      African would-be immigrants sleep in their dormitory in an enclosed compound at the Safi detention centre outside Valletta July 15, 2008. Around 1,500 illegal immigrants are currently held in detention in Malta for periods of up to 18 months. Though their intention was to reach Italy, most found themselves in Malta when they were rescued by the Maltese Armed Forces when they found themselves in difficulties while on their way to reach European soil from Africa. Photo: Darrin Zammit Lupi
    - TV room (1), 2008 July 15; Original file id: _JM97753 (Digital-materials RL11613-SET-0005, Image-file RL.11613-TIFF-0125)
      African would-be immigrants watch television in their common room in an enclosed compound at the Safi detention centre outside Valletta July 15, 2008. Around 1,500 illegal immigrants are currently held in detention in Malta for periods of up to 18 months. Though their intention was to reach Italy, most found themselves in Malta when they were rescued by the Maltese Armed Forces when they found themselves in difficulties while on their way to reach European soil from Africa. Photo: Darrin Zammit Lupi
    - Wondering what it's like out there, 2008 July 15; Original file id: _C4W1417 (Digital-materials RL11613-SET-0005, Image-file RL.11613-TIFF-0126)
      An African would-be immigrant holds onto a perimeter fence in an enclosed compound at the Safi detention centre outside Valletta July 15, 2008. Around 1,500 illegal immigrants are currently held in detention in Malta for periods of up to 18 months. Though their intention was to reach Italy, most found themselves in Malta when they were rescued by the Maltese Armed Forces when they found themselves in difficulties while on their way to reach European soil from Africa. Photo: Darrin Zammit Lupi
    - Killing time (3), 2008 July 15; Original file id: _JM97789 (Digital-materials RL11613-SET-0005, Image-file RL.11613-TIFF-0127)
    - Killing time (4), 2008 July 15; Original file id: _JM97802 (Digital-materials RL11613-SET-0005, Image-file RL.11613-TIFF-0128)
      An African would-be immigrant sleeps on a mattress in an enclosed compound at the Safi detention centre outside Valletta July 15, 2008. Though all migrants are provided with beds, many prefer to sleep on mattresses on the floor. Around 1,500 illegal immigrants are currently held in detention in Malta for periods of up to 18 months. Though their intention was to reach Italy, most found themselves in Malta when they were rescued by the Maltese Armed Forces when they found themselves in difficulties while on their way to reach European soil from Africa. Photo: Darrin Zammit Lupi
    - Morning exercise, 2008 July 15; Original file id: _C4W1469 (Digital-materials RL11613-SET-0005, Image-file RL.11613-TIFF-0129)
      African would-be immigrants exercise in an enclosed compound at the Safi detention centre outside Valletta July 15, 2008. Around 1,500 illegal immigrants are currently held in detention in Malta for periods of up to 18 months. Though their intention was to reach Italy, most found themselves in Malta when they were rescued by the Maltese Armed Forces when they found themselves in difficulties while on their way to reach European soil from Africa. Photo: Darrin Zammit Lupi
    - Basic supplies (1), 2008 July 15; Original file id: _JM97816 (Digital-materials RL11613-SET-0005, Image-file RL.11613-TIFF-0130)
      Basic clothing and toiletry supplies which are given to each newly-arrived would-be immigrant are seen at the Safi detention centre outside Valletta July 15, 2008. Around 1,500 illegal immigrants are currently held in detention in Malta for periods of up to 18 months. Though their intention was to reach Italy, most found themselves in Malta when they were rescued by the Maltese Armed Forces when they found themselves in difficulties while on their way to reach European soil from Africa. Photo: Darrin Zammit Lupi
    - Basic supplies (2), 2008 July 15; Original file id: _JM97817 (Digital-materials RL11613-SET-0005, Image-file RL.11613-TIFF-0131)
    - Technician Yakubu Ramanu, 2008 July 15; Original file id: _JM97833 (Digital-materials RL11613-SET-0005, Image-file RL.11613-TIFF-0132)
      Yakubu Ramanu (R), a 26-year-old would-be immigrant from Togo and a technician, repairs a fellow detainee's radio in an enclosed compound at the Safi detention centre outside Valletta July 15, 2008. Around 1,500 illegal immigrants are currently held in detention in Malta for periods of up to 18 months. Though their intention was to reach Italy, most found themselves in Malta when they were rescued by the Maltese Armed Forces when they found themselves in difficulties while on their way to reach European soil from Africa. Photo: Darrin Zammit Lupi
    - Draughts, 2008 July 15; Original file id: _JM97867 (Digital-materials RL11613-SET-0005, Image-file RL.11613-TIFF-0133)
      African would-be immigrants play a game of draughts in their common room in an enclosed compound at the Safi detention centre outside Valletta July 15, 2008. Around 1,500 illegal immigrants are currently held in detention in Malta for periods of up to 18 months. Though their intention was to reach Italy, most found themselves in Malta when they were rescued by the Maltese Armed Forces when they found themselves in difficulties while on their way to reach European soil from Africa. Photo: Darrin Zammit Lupi
    - Sitting in the corridor, 2008 July 15; Original file id: _JM97896 (Digital-materials RL11613-SET-0005, Image-file RL.11613-TIFF-0134)
      An African would-be immigrant sits in a corridor in an enclosed compound at the Safi detention centre outside Valletta July 15, 2008. Around 1,500 illegal immigrants are currently held in detention in Malta for periods of up to 18 months. Though their intention was to reach Italy, most found themselves in Malta when they were rescued by the Maltese Armed Forces when they found themselves in difficulties while on their way to reach European soil from Africa. Photo: Darrin Zammit Lupi
    - Taking out the trash (1), 2008 July 15; Original file id: _JM97905 (Digital-materials RL11613-SET-0005, Image-file RL.11613-TIFF-0135)
      African would-be immigrants carry a garbage can through corridor in an enclosed compound at the Safi detention centre outside Valletta July 15, 2008. Around 1,500 illegal immigrants are currently held in detention in Malta for periods of up to 18 months. Though their intention was to reach Italy, most found themselves in Malta when they were rescued by the Maltese Armed Forces when they found themselves in difficulties while on their way to reach European soil from Africa. Photo: Darrin Zammit Lupi
    - On the stairs, 2008 July 15; Original file id: _JM97914 (Digital-materials RL11613-SET-0005, Image-file RL.11613-TIFF-0136)
      An African would-be immigrant stands on an outside staircase in an enclosed compound at the Safi detention centre outside Valletta July 15, 2008. Around 1,500 illegal immigrants are currently held in detention in Malta for periods of up to 18 months. Though their intention was to reach Italy, most found themselves in Malta when they were rescued by the Maltese Armed Forces when they found themselves in difficulties while on their way to reach European soil from Africa. Photo: Darrin Zammit Lupi
    - Taking out the trash (2), 2008 July 15; Original file id: _JM97917 (Digital-materials RL11613-SET-0005, Image-file RL.11613-TIFF-0137)